ゴキッ
（葉風）うっ…。
今日で１３０日…。
Today marks the 131st day I've been here.
この生活にも　さすがに飽きたな。
I must say that I'm getting tired of this.
（不破真広・通信）
お目覚めか？　のんきなもんだな。
You awake?
Must be nice.
こっちは歩きづめだが　なかなか
黒鉄病の範囲から抜けられねぇ。
We've been walking for a while,
but we can't seem to escape the area affected by Black Iron Syndrome.
（葉風・通信）絶園の果実は？
飛んだ方向は記録しただろうな？
And the Fruit of Exodus?
You noted its direction, didn't you?
一応はな。
（滝川吉野）ほんとに　これで？
Yeah, more or less.
Is this really...
（葉風・通信）
ああ　必ず絞り込める→
Yes, this should lead
目指すべき場所をな。
to your desired destination.
（夏村）失礼します。
≫ガラガラ（扉の音）
Pardon.
≫（夏村）お疲れのご様子。
You seem tired.
（左門）錯覚だ。
儀式を手伝わせてすまんな。
It's just your imagination.
I apologize for asking you to assist with the ritual.
（夏村）いえ。　ただ…。
No, it's just...
You want to know where those two are headed.
（左門）
あの二人の動向が気になる…　か？
（夏村）はい。
望んだ相手を探す術があれば→
Yes.
If we had the means to find those we seek,
すぐ捕らえられるのですが…。
I could apprehend them quickly.
However, our magic preserves and corrects logic.
（左門）我らが魔法は
理を守り　正す力だ。→
If someone were to kill another,
we could use our magic to find them,
人を殺すといった
世の理を犯した者なら→
in order to right that wrong.
それを正すためとして探せるが
でなければ無理だな。
Otherwise, it's impossible.
（夏村）ただ　同様に　あの二人も→
On the other hand, I doubt those two
この場所を　たやすくは
見つけられないでしょう→
will be able to find this place easily, either.
結界で守られ　この異変さえ
外からは見えないのですから。
This location is protected by a barrier,
and it cannot be seen from the outside.
But there are clues.
（左門）だが　手がかりは残る。→
The fruits that fly into the air head almost directly for the Tree of Exodus.
空に上がった果実は　ほぼ一直線で
絶園の樹へ向かって飛ぶ。
If they were to follow the various fruits' trajectories,
さまざまの場所から飛んだ
複数の果実の方向を測れば→
and examine them on a map,
その軌道は
必然的に一点で交わる→
it would be possible
この地でな。
to pinpoint this place.
そして　果実は
すでに５つ以上飛んでいる。
Five fruits are already in flight.
（夏村）では　姫様は…。
Then the princess...
（左門）
間違いなく絞り込んでいよう。
I'm sure she's narrowed it down to this site.
It's like her hands are already around our throats.
姫様の手は
こちらの喉元にかかったも同じだ。
すでに拠点は絞れた。→
We've already deduced the location.
貴様らが　私に従えば
あと数手で　左門を詰められる。→
If you listen to me,
you'll be able to find Samon soon enough.
Listen.
（通信）いいか？
魔法使いとしては　私が最強だ。→
As a mage, I am superior.
一族の力を全て合わせても
取るに足らん。→
Even the combined power of the clan would be no match for me.
私が敵対すれば
その時点で　左門の負けは決まる。
If I were to oppose him,
Samon's downfall would be decided at that moment.
だから
ろくに魔法を使えないそこに→
And that's why he trapped you on that island,
あなたを放り出したんでしょう？
（葉風・通信）そうだ。
where you can barely use magic.
That's right.
だが　左門は　私を殺さなかった。
But Samon didn't kill me.
殺してしまえば
後の憂いもないというのに→
If he'd killed me, he wouldn't have had to worry over possible consequences.
Instead, he went to the trouble of trapping me on this island.
あえて孤島に閉じ込めるという
面倒を選んだ。
なぜだと思う？
Why do you suppose that is?
（左門）
本来　絶園の樹の復活を早め→
Our attempt to accelerate the Tree of Exodus's rebirth
制御しようということ自体に
無理がある。
and control it is fundamentally implausible.
One mistake,
一つ間違えば　その恐るべき
破壊の力を扱いきれず→
and there would be no stopping its destructive power.
Return! Return! Return! Return!
目的を果たすどころか
取り返しのつかんことになる。
Not only could we not carry out our plan,
but we would be unable to recover from the consequences.
（男たち）戻れ　戻れ→
戻れ　戻れ。
If the Tree of Exodus were to go berserk,
もし　絶園の樹が狂嵐となれば→
even hundred mages of Samon's caliber couldn't hope to control it.
左門ごときが１００人いても
その力は抑えられん。→
I'm the only one who can do that.
（通信）
それを抑えられるのは　私だけだ。
つまり　左門が
お前を生かしておいたのは→
Which means Samon kept you alive as insurance,
万が一のときの保険ってわけだ。
just in case something went wrong.
そう。　左門は　堅実な男だ。
Precisely.
Samon is a smart man.
常に最悪を考え
その対策を用意する。
He always considers a worst case scenario and prepares for it.
だから　まさかのとき→
So for that unlikely eventuality
he's made plans to return me to Japan.
いつでも　私を
日本に戻せる用意をしている→
必ずな。
No matter what.
Return! Return! Return!
Although the princess found people to assist from the mainland,
姫様は　本土に協力者を
見つけたからといって→
自分がいる島を探させはしない。
she'd never have them try to locate her island.
That would take too much time and money.
それには
時間も金も　かかりすぎる。
The princess intends to interfere with the revival of the Tree of Exodus,
姫様は
絶園の樹の復活を妨害させ→
絶園の力を狂わせようとする→
to derail the power of Exodus.
At any cost.
必ずな。→
力が狂えば→
If the power were to go out of control,
I would have no choice but to bring the princess back.
私は　姫様を　島から
ここに戻さざるをえない。→
And should the princess return,
そして　姫様が戻れば
最悪は避けられても→
the worst could be avoided, but we would lose.
我らの負けだ。
（葉風）もとより困難な
絶園の樹の復活を→
They've spent only four months to prepare
僅か４か月ばかりの準備で
行っているのだ。
for the difficult task of reviving the Tree of Exodus.
外部からの妨害で
あっけなく崩れるぞ。
Any outside interference would guarantee a miserable failure.
Samon stands beneath the sword.
左門は　剣の下に立っているよ。
姫様のことです→
Since it's the princess we're talking about,
妨害に足る　強力な魔具を
用意しているのでは？
I'm sure she's prepared some powerful talisman to obstruct us.
（左門）同じ心配をするものだな。
You are not the only one to share that concern.
（夏村）誰とです？
（左門）哲馬だ。→
Who else does?
Tetsuma.
He's currently following the princess to all the places she's been that we know of.
分かる範囲で　かつて
姫様が赴いた場所を当たっている。
自信満々じゃねぇか　姫様は。
The princess seems pretty confident.
はじまりの樹に
庇護されているって思いが→
Well, she's certain that the Tree of Genesis is protecting her.
葉風さんの根底にあるから。
はぁ…
よく分からねぇ根拠だがな。
Though the basis for that certainty is a bit dubious.
（心の声）≪この世の理を
造り　守る　はじまりの樹≫
The Tree of Genesis makes and protects the reasoning of this world.
And the Tree of Exodus severs and destroys the reasoning of this world.
≪そして　この世の理を
断ち　砕く　絶園の樹≫
≪かつて　この世を
破壊しようとした絶園の樹は→
The Tree of Exodus once tried to destroy the world,
はじまりの樹に敗れ
その身をバラバラにされ→
but it lost to the Tree of Genesis and was hewn apart and sealed away.
封じられた≫
≪一方で
はじまりの樹も深く傷つき→
However, the Tree of Genesis was also grievously injured,
なんとか　世界を支えながらも→
so it sleeps, in an attempt to recover, even as it supports this world.
今は
再生のために眠っているという≫
≪鎖部一族の役目は
はじまりの樹が→
The Kusaribe clan's duty
is to retrieve the Tree of Exodus's fruit,
再生するときまで　絶園の樹が
果実となった身を集め→
to prevent it from reviving before the Tree of Genesis awakens.
復活するのを抑えること≫
And because of that, it is said
≪そのため　一族の者は→
はじまりの樹の理を
借り受けることができるという≫
that the Kusaribe clan can borrow power from the Tree of Genesis.
And that the Tree of Genesis protects their princess...
≪そして　そのはじまりの樹に
守られている一族の姫…≫
≪何もかも
彼女の思いどおりに進むのは→
It might be obvious to assume
that all will go as she expects.
当然ということに
なるのかもしれないけど…≫
But something doesn't feel right.
≪でも　どうも引っ掛かる≫
おい　吉野。
Hey, Yoshino.
あれじゃねぇのか？
That's the place, isn't it?
Episode 5
Everything
Happens for a Reason
（葉風・通信）
鯨の骨格標本が中庭にある。→
There's a reassembled skeleton of a whale in the inner courtyard.
I buried the talisman nearby.
魔具は　その近くに埋めた。
どうして　こんな所に？
Why here?
No specific reason.
（葉風・通信）
どうということもないが…→
昔　村の子供たちと
この辺りに遊びに来たことがある。
I'd simply visited there before with the clan children.
I haven't been to an aquarium since I was a kid.
水族館なんて
俺も　ガキのころ以来だぜ。
How about you?
お前は？
えっ？
Huh?
まあ　そうかな…。
Yeah, me neither...
Let's hurry up and finish this.
さっさと　用件　済まそうぜ。
（部下）あの二人…。
（哲馬）おそらくな。→
Are those two...
Most likely.
Very few humans can move freely within the boundaries set by the Black Iron Syndrome.
黒鉄病の影響範囲で
動ける人間など　限られている。→
左門殿に
またとない手土産ができそうだ。
It appears I'll have quite the gift for Mr. Samon.
Stuffed models everywhere...
ガッチガチの剥製だらけだな。
ああ。
Yeah.
It seems more like a museum than an aquarium.
水族館ってより　博物館って感じ。
（愛花・回想）((吉野さん→
Yoshino,
everything happens for a reason.
全てのことには
わけがあるんです。→
日々起こる　悲劇も不幸も→
The daily tragedies and misfortunes are all meaningful events,
いつか起こる
最良の結末のための→
価値ある出来事なんです。→
that lead toward an ideal conclusion.
With that in mind,
その意味では　ただの不幸なんて
ないのかもしれません))
there probably isn't really any meaningless misfortune.
((ふふっ　それくらい→
It'd be nice if life went that smoothly.
人生が　うまくいってくれると
いいんだけどね))
（愛花）((そうでも思わないと→
Well, if I don't think of it that way,
真広みたいのが兄だなんて
やってられませんから))
I doubt I could handle having Mahiro as an older brother.
((でも　あいつは
愛花ちゃんを大事にしてるよ))
But he cares a lot about you.
And because of that,
（愛花）((そのせいで
吉野さんと　こうしているのを→
we have to hide our involvement from him.
真広に隠さないといけませんね))
If he found out, I wouldn't put it past him to bury me alive.
((そりゃ　バレたら生き埋めにでも
されかねないからね))
((ふふっ))
Even so,
((それでも　全てのことには
わけがあります))
everything happens for a reason.
Someday, this will also have a very beautiful outcome.
((これも　いつかは
美しい結末の伏線になるでしょう))
There are more things in heaven and earth, Horatio,
((「ホレイショー
この天地のあいだには→
than are dreamt of in your philosophy.
人間の学問などの
夢にも思いおよばぬことが→
いくらでもあるのだ」))
((僕は　ホレイショーじゃないよ))
I'm not Horatio.
Besides,
((それに→
I don't think you have to bring up Hamlet at a time like this...
こういうとき　「ハムレット」の
セリフを引用しなくても…))
≪愛花ちゃん…　君は
本当に　そう思っていたのか？≫
Aika,
was that what you really thought?
≪本当に　全てのことには
わけがあるって…≫
Did you truly believe that everything happens for a reason?
おい　吉野　そっちは？
Hey, Yoshino... Any luck over there?
あっ…。
見つけたか？
Did you find it?
どうした？
あっ　いや…　なんでもない。
What's wrong?
Oh, it's nothing...
（葉風・通信）回収は？
終わった。
How goes the recovery?
We found it.
（葉風・通信）よし　あとは…。
待て。
All right, then...
Wait.
槍男…　いや　一人じゃねぇな。
The spear guy?
No, there are more.
Spear guy?
（哲馬）槍男…　ふっ。
I assume you mean Natsumura.
夏村のことか。
で　お次は　矢印野郎。
And now, we have arrow guy.
葉風　お前の一族は
みんな　キャラが立ってんなぁ。
Hakaze, people from your clan sure are easy to spot.
哲馬だな。　頭は切れるが→
That must be Tetsuma.
He's smart, but also full of conceit.
（通信）こざかしい男だ。
ふん　相変わらず　お口が悪い。
I see you have not lost your sharp tongue.
（葉風・通信）久しいな　哲馬。
It's been a while, Tetsuma.
（哲馬）麗しいお姿を
見られぬのが残念です。
I am sad that I cannot see your beauty in person.
（葉風・通信）心にもないことを…。
Stop saying things you don't mean.
Do not lay a finger on those two.
この二人には　手を出すな。
（哲馬・通信）
黙って　ついてきてもらえば→
If they come along quietly,
things won't have to get violent.
手荒なまねはいたしません。
だいたい　左門殿の言葉に→
Not to mention,
if only you'd had the heart to listen to Mr. Samon to begin with,
耳を傾ける度量が
あなたにあれば→
この者たちを
巻き込む必要などなかった。
these two wouldn't have had to get involved.
The purpose of our clan is to revive the Tree of Genesis.
（葉風・通信）はじまりの樹を
復活させるのが　我が一族の理。
なぜ　理に背こうとするのだ。
Why would you rebel against that?
昔から　独りよがりで→
You have always been self-righteous, with no qualms about imposing your will on others.
周りを
振り回してきた　あなたです。→
ここまで分別つかぬまま
お育ちになるとは→
To think that you would become so oblivious...
あきれて　物も…。
（葉風・通信）分からぬか？→
I doubt I have words—
Do you not understand?
What you are doing is betrayal.
お前たちの行為は裏切りなのだぞ。
あなたが
島で朽ち果てるのが一族のため。
It's best for the clan that you perish on that island...
そう思っているのは→
I highly doubt I'm the sole person to feel that way.
（通信）私だけではないはず。
（通信）おい　葉風。
Hey, Hakaze...
長話は
そのくらいにしたらどうだ？
Want to cut the chatter there?
あいにくだが
おとなしくついていく気は→
Unfortunately, I have no intention of coming along quietly!
これっぽっちもねぇ！
うっ！
真広！
Mahiro!
ドォーーーン！
真広　こっちだ！
Mahiro, over here!
ごほごほっ！
くそっ！　逃がすな！
Damn it.
Don't let them escape!
ふん！
ガン！
退くぞ！
Let's go!
ここまで来れば
しばらくは大丈夫だ。
Having gotten this far, we should be okay for a bit.
That was pretty bold of you.
思い切ったことしやがって。
ははっ…。
((だから　いいよ
こういうの　あまり着けないし))
Really, it's okay.
I don't wear things like this,
((それに　ちょっと
子供っぽすぎるような…))
and it looks too childish.
（愛花）((人が
プレゼントしようというのに→
You shouldn't complain when someone's trying to give you a gift.
文句を言うものではありません))
((それに
こういう平凡なものの方が→
Anyway,
ordinary things like this suit you.
吉野さんには似合います))
((随分な…))
That's rather...
It doesn't matter how boring it is.
((どんなものだろうと
贈り物一つで→
そこに
物語が芽生えたりするものです))
A single gift is the start of a new story.
((美しい結末の？))
（愛花）((さあ？→
Leading to a beautiful outcome?
Well...
それは　どうでしょう))
((ん？))
Who knows?
((ふふっ　やっぱり変かも))
Actually, it may look a little odd.
((ふふふふっ))
There's nothing strange about that.
≪動揺することなんて何もない≫
≪どこの水族館で売っていても
おかしくない→
That boring necklace could be sold at any aquarium.
平凡なネックレス≫
It was just a weird coincidence.
≪たまたま
つながっただけの偶然≫
((それでも　全てのことには…))
Even so, everything...
あの矢印野郎に
随分と嫌われてるみたいだな。
Seems like the arrow guy doesn't like you much.
（葉風・通信）昔から
私に反抗的なヤツではあった。
He's always been defiant toward me.
クソ生意気な姫様には
誰でも逆らいたくなるもんだぜ。
Well, anyone would be defiant with a selfish little princess.
（葉風・通信）真面目に聞け。→
Seriously, listen to me.
Perhaps it's because of his intelligence,
あいつは　下手に頭が切れるせいか
理に落ちぬことを　ひどく嫌う。
but he hates anything that defies reason.
（通信）魔法使いの一族のくせに？
鎖部の魔法は→
Yet he's part of a clan of mages?
The Kusaribe clan magic
はじまりの樹に　供物を与える
見返りとして　力を授かる。→
derives from our offerings to the Tree of Genesis.
合理的なギブ・アンド・テイクの
構造が　一応はある。
It's technically a reasonable give and take.
But because the Tree of Genesis protects me,
だが　はじまりの樹によって
庇護されている私のあり方は→
理屈のつかぬものに
ヤツには見えるらしい。
he seems to find my circumstance illogical.
Well, yeah.
確かにな。　お前に言わせりゃ→
According to you, our meeting wasn't just by chance, either.
俺と知り合ったことも
ただの偶然じゃねぇってことになる。
That's right...
（葉風）そうだ
それさえも導かれた運命。→
That, too, was guided by fate.
理が理によって
定義できぬというのは→
It may be an irony that reason cannot be defined by logic.
皮肉な話かもしれん。→
But regardless, a logic still underlies everything.
（通信）
だが　それでも　全てのことには→
理が働いているのだ。
違う。
No.
ん？
（葉風・通信）なぜだ？→
Why not?
How can you say it's not so?
なぜ　違うと断言できる。
あっ…。
Um...
いや　なんでも…。
Never mind that.
≪全てのことに　わけがあるなら→
If everything happens for a reason...
君が無残に殺されたのは→
Are you telling me that the reason
you were brutally killed was so Mahiro would save the world?
真広に世界を救わせるためだった
とでもいうのかい？≫
吉野→
Yoshino.
Could you act as bait and lure them in?
おとりになって
連中を引き寄せてくれねぇか？
What are you considering?
何をやろうと…。
さっきのお前と似たようなことだ。
Something similar to what you did earlier...
魚になってな…。
But as a fish.
（２人）あっ！
≪（部下）いたぞ！
There he is!
どこに行った!?
Where'd he go?
（哲馬）ううっ…　くそっ！
Damn it!
Don't move.
動くな。
（哲馬）何ぃ!?
What?
It appears that aquariums use quite a bit of electricity.
水族館ってのは
案外　電気をくう施設みてぇだな。
部下を引き連れて帰りな→
Take your lackeys and get out.
こんなとこで
感電したくなけりゃな。
Unless you wanna get fried here.
（葉風・通信）言うとおりにした方が
身のためだぞ。→
It'd probably be wise to obey him.
こやつは　やると言えば　やる男だ。
He's a man of his word.
Was it really okay to let them go like that?
あのまま逃がして
よかったのかなぁ？
Should we have been more dramatic?
もっと過激にやりたかったか？
いや…。
No...
でも　こちらの動きが…。
But now they know where we are.
（葉風・通信）伝わったところで
どうということもなかろう。
That won't really change anything.
Once we recover the special talisman,
（葉風）特製の魔具を回収すれば
あとは　こちらから攻め込む以外→
there aren't many other options beyond moving forward with our attack plans.
あまり選択の余地もない。
（通信）特製の魔具？
A special talisman?
Just as it implies, it's a talisman with special power.
言葉どおり
特別な力を持つ魔具だ→
Quite an amount of it too.
そら恐ろしいほどのな。→
（通信）だから
こればかりは　信用できる相手に→
This is why I have someone I really trust holding it for me.
預かってもらっている。
お前が　他人を信用するのか？
You actually trust people?
（葉風・通信）一人だけ…
一族の中で　妙な立場にあってな→
Just one.
He's someone in the clan who ended up in an unusual situation.
今も大学生のはずだ。→
He should be a college student.
のんきな人だから
変わらず同じ所で暮らしていよう。
He's somewhat carefree, so I'm sure he still lives in the same place.
So this person is on your side?
（通信）その人は　葉風さんの側に
ついてくれてるわけ？
どちらでもない。→
He's not on either side.
というか　そういうゴタゴタに
巻き込まれるのを避けるように→
Or rather, he left to avoid getting involved in this mess at all.
去っていった。
（子供）((ふふっ))
（子供）((あはははっ))
Let's go over here.
（子供）((あっち行こう))
（子供たち）((ふふふふっ))
Princess?
You don't look very happy.
((なんか　元気ないぞ))
((すまんな))
My apologies.
Is it because Mr. Junichiro left?
Why'd he leave?
((潤兄さんは
争い事が嫌いだからな))
Junichiro doesn't really like to fight.
Samon.
（葉風）((左門))
（左門）((お話があります))
May I have a word?
Well, well. Aren't you all formal?
((随分と仰々しいな。
いよいよ　最終通告とでも…))
Have you come with your ultimatum?
((あっ))
((こら！　堂々と盗んでいくな！))
Hey! Don't be so brazen about stealing my things!
（左門）((姫様のお力に
畏敬の念を抱くがゆえです))
It is because we fear and respect your power.
((なるほど　私の身の回りから→
I see,
so you tricked these children into luring me here,
供物となるものを
遠ざけるために→
keeping me from getting my hands on any items.
この子らも唆し
私を誘い込んだか))
((ああ　お前たちは　ただ
私と遊びたかっただけだ))
Oh, I know that you two just wanted to play.
((何も問題はない))
You don't have anything to worry about.
((姫様のエッチな格好が
見たかったのか？))
Do they want to see you naked?
((そんなようなものだ))
Something like that.
((見るからに
ムッツリスケベという顔だろう))
You can totally tell that they're closet perverts.
（左門）((もう一度
じっくり話し合う時間を頂きたい))
I would like another opportunity for us to have a discussion.
((私の屋敷まで
お越しいただけませんか？))
Would you please accompany me to my manor?
((嫌だと言えば？))
((不本意ながら　力ずくでも))
And if I refuse?
I would prefer not to use force.
((抵抗するつもりはない))
I don't plan to resist.
But...
（葉風）((左門　貴様では勝てん))
Samon.
You cannot win.
As long as the world's logic sides with me,
((世の理が
私と共にあるかぎり→
you have no chance of victory.
貴様に勝機は巡りはしない))
（左門）((姫様…
姫様に勝とうなど　この左門→
Princess,
I have never...
一度たりとて
考えたことはございません。→
The thought of victory against you has never crossed my mind.
ただ　いま一度…))
But please...
((いま一度
話し合う機会を頂きたい…→
But please allow me the chance to speak with you.
Please believe in me.
この左門を信じて))
Return! Return! Return!
（夏村）左門殿→
Mr. Samon.
哲馬殿から連絡があり→
I have just heard from Tetsuma
例の二人を見つけたものの
取り逃がしたと。
that he located those two, but had to let them escape.
I see.
（左門）
そうか…　やはり動いているか。
So they're making their move.
（男たち）戻れ　戻れ　戻れ　戻れ→
戻れ　戻れ。
Ahead
Tsuk
ada
chou
It should be somewhere around here...
ここら辺で間違いないんだけど。
あれじゃねぇか？
Maybe that's it...
I must emphasize that you should not tell Junichiro about my current situation.
（葉風）念を押すが　潤兄さんには→
私の現状については　一切話すな。
なるべく心配をさせたくない。→
I'd prefer that he not worry...
（通信）
ただ魔具を受け取れ。　いいな？
Just get the talisman, understand?
コンコン
≪（潤一郎）はい。
Yes?
（潤一郎）どちらさまで？
Who might you be?
Sorry for coming by so late.
あっ…
夜分遅く申し訳ありません。
星村…　鎖部潤一郎さんですね？
（潤一郎）はあ。
You're Hoshimura...
Kusaribe Junichiro, right?
Yes...
葉風さんからの依頼で
魔具を受け取りに来ました。
Ms. Hakaze requested that we retrieve a talisman from you.
葉風ちゃんの？
入っていいか？
A request from Hakaze?
Can we come in?
Um, just in case, could you say the password?
（潤一郎）あっ…
一応　合言葉を言ってくれる？
「揺れないちちは　ちちじゃない」。
Boobs that don't shake aren't boobs at all.
オッケー。　じゃあ　中に。
Okay.
Come on in.
≪この合言葉
誰の趣味なんだろ…≫
Who the hell came up with that password?
（潤一郎）しかし　あの子が
そこまで考えていたとはね。→
To think...
that she thought this far ahead...
君たちも災難だったね
葉風ちゃんに見込まれるなんて。→
How unfortunate for you,
that Hakaze took a liking to you.
昔は　おもらしもする→
She used to be a cute little kid who wet her bed.
（通信）かわいい子だったんだよ。
Hurry up...
早くしろよ。
俺らが暇そうに見えるか？
Do we look like we have this much time?
真広…。
うん。　それも　もっともな話か。
Mahiro...
It must be serious.
≪なんか
恐ろしく動じない人だな≫
He's unusually calm...
≪仏壇？≫
A Buddhist altar?
（潤一郎）あった。→
Here it is.
預けられたときのままだけど
壊れたりはしてないと思うよ。
I haven't touched it since I received it,
so it shouldn't be broken.
あっ　どうも。
Oh, thank you.
（潤一郎）
線香くらい　上げていくかい？
Did you want to light some incense before you go?
あの…　どなたのです？
Um...
For whom?
（潤一郎）葉風ちゃんだよ。
（２人）なっ…。
For Hakaze.
もしかして
彼女が亡くなったの知らなかった？
You two didn't know she died?
That Samon...
左門め
私が死んだと言ってあるのか！
He's saying that I'm dead?
おい！
そんなこと言われて信じたのか!?
You believed that just because someone told you so?
Of course not.
（潤一郎）
まさか。　そんな単純じゃないよ。
I'm not that simple-minded.
でも　これは間違いない。→
But there's no doubt.
I verified her body.
僕は
彼女の遺体を確認したんだ。→
She died on an island, next to a barrel.
彼女は
孤島で　樽と共に死んでいる。
（左門）はじまりの理が
姫様に味方をしようと→
Even if the logic of Genesis sides with the princess,
勝つための切り札はある。
we have a trump card to assure our victory.
姫様は今でも　樽の中だ。
The princess is still
inside a barrel.
kimi to miteta nagareboshi oikakete
Chasing the shooting star that we saw together
Reaching this place all alone
hitori bocchi konna toko made kiteta
Hiding the feelings I wanted to express to you
kinou kimi ni ienakatta kimochi o
kotoba no naka kakusu no
within words
tooku hanarete itemo douka todokimasu you ni
No matter how far we are separated,
please let it reach you
kono michi no saki ni matsu unmei nante
The fate waiting for us down this road
is not yet known
ima wa mada
dare mo mada
shiranai kedo
by anyone
To the future drawn by numbed fingers
kajikan da yubisaki de egaita mirai he
With you we can make it
kimi to nara ikerutte
nee sonna ki ga shiteta nda
That's what I feel
kitto
with certainty
Make sure the princess dies.
（左門）姫様を亡き者にした。
（愛花）あなたは　私と→
What relationship do you want to have with me?
どうなりたいんですか？
I will save you.
俺が　お前を救ってやるよ。
（早河）我々は
魔法使いに　戦争を仕掛ける。
We'll wage war on the mages.
（山本）
これで　私も魔法使いの仲間入り？
Now I can join the club as a mage, too!
I always did think she had a nicely shaped head.
（潤一郎）あの子の頭の形
きれいだったから。
There are no such things as ghosts.
（葉風）幽霊など　この世におらん。
Episode 6
The Paradox
of the Skull